Sergio Villarroel

Software Developer QA Developer

Personal Info

PHONE

E-MAIL

sergioworking247@gmail.com

PLACE & DATE OF BIRTH Colorado, USA. November 13th 1993

LINKEDIN

www.linkedin.com/in/sergiovillap

Skill Highlights

- Python, Django, React, JS, MongoDB, GraphQL, AWS
- Java EE, Hibernate, JSF, JSP, Spring, JSON, REST
- Web Testing & Automatization (Selenium Suite, Python, Javascript and Jenkins)
- Agile/Scrum Methodology
- Performance Optimization
- SQL, MySQL, Oracle Database
- · Git, Git Bash
- Basic Knowledge: HTML5,

PHP, CSS, React.

- Platforms: Windows, Linux.
- TensorFlow

Languages

English: Native

Spanish: Native

Web Developer and QA Developer with a strong background in Software Development with 5+ years of experience. Skilled in manual and automated testing and creating test plans. I've been involved in every step of web and software development implementing agile methodology and generating extensive documentation of tests and results. My previous employments provided me with experiences and multiple skills that allow me to effectively communicate remotely with other team members and customers to achieve goals and achieve customer satisfaction.

Experience

Present -

Web Developer & QA Developer Freelance for multiple projects

2020-04

- Developed QA Automated Tests implementing Python, JS, Selenium, Django, MySQL, Bash and AWS which ensured a faster and more reliable commit by decreasing bugs 20%.
- Implemented multiple solutions for an eCommerce with Django, React, Python, Rest, GraphQl, MongoDB, Docker and AWS

2020-04 -2017-05

Java Developer / QA Analyst and Developer

Accenture - Oracle CC&B

- Managed a small team focused on developing a testing tool based in python and Selenium web Driver which applied a light layer of Machine Learning and Database feedback for testing new implementations automatically.
- Modified existing software of Oracle's billing and customer care application using Java, Hibernate and spring to correct bugs along with improving performance and upgrading interfaces.
- Worked closely with Project Manager in a successful migration backing up databases, restoring and updating the billing application for a major Argentinian energy company.

2016-12 - **SAP Consultant**

2014-05

IBM - Document Management System Module

- Consulted with clients regularly regarding projects, proposals, and technical issues that arise during the development process, while collaborating with other team members to determine the best design specifications and application of solutions
- Designed and mapped internal workflows for legal, planning and confidential documents, and developed a file management system.
- Prepared reports on specifications and activities for each project.
- Quickly learned Abap and provided support finding bugs and developing solutions.

Courses

- QA Testing of software solutions
- Automation with Python (Google)
- Advanced Java (Threads, OO, Servlets)
- Hibernate, Java EE, JSP, JSF
- Maven Web Applications

Education

2014-05-Present UADE (Argentinian University of Business)
Bachelor's Degree Computer Science (5th Year)